

git clone <url>
git add <file>
git status
git commit -a
i 
esc
:x!
git push





Version Control

1. Centralized Version Control vs. Distributed Version Control
2. distributed is the new-centralized

3. Unlike other version control systems, Git thinks of its data more like a series of snapshots of a miniature system, instead of a list of file-based changes. With Git, every time you commit, or save the state of your project, Git basically takes a picture of what all your files look like at that moment and stores a reference to that snapshot. To be efficient, if files haven't changed, Git doesn't store the file again, just a link to the previous identical file it has already stored. Fit thinks about its data more like a stream of snapshots. 
4. You can also be productive if you are offline or off VPN. If you get on an airplane or a train and want to do a little work, you can commit happily to you local copy, until you get to a network connection to upload. 

5. The 3 states: Git has 3 main states that your files can reside in: committed, modified, and stages.
	Modified: you have changed the file but haven't committed it to your database yet.
	Staged: you have marked a modified file in its current version to go into your next commit snapshot.
	Committed: the data is safely stored in your local databases.

6. Working Directory (working tree)-> Staging Area -> .Git directory (repository)
The Git directory is where Git stores the metadata and object database for your project. This is the most important part of Git, and it is what is copied when you clone a repository from another computer.
The working tree is a single checkout of one version of the project. These files are pulled out of the compressed database in the Git directory and placed on disk for you to use or modify.
The staging area is a file, generally contained in your Git directory, that stores information about what will go into your next commit.

7. Basic Git workflow goes something like this:
	1. You modify files in your working tree.
	2. You selectively stage just those changes you want to be part of your next commit, which adds only those changes to the staging area.
	3. You do a commit, which takes the files as they are in the staging area and stores that snapshot permanently to your Git directory.

Git Command Line

1. Installing Git
	git --version
2. Getting help
	git help <verb>
	man git-<verb>
3. Get a Git Repository
You can take a local directory that is currently not under version control, and turn it into a Git repository. Or you can clone an existing Git repository from elsewhere. 
	git clone <http> [<alias>]

4. Recording changes to the repository
At this point, you should have a Git repository on your local machine. 
Each file in your working directory can be in one of two states: tracked or untracked.
Tracked files: files that were in the last snapshot; they can be unmodified, modified, or staged. In short, tracked files are files that Git knows about.
Untracked files: any files in your working directory that were not in your last snapshot and are not in your staging area. 

Untracked -> Unmodified -> Modified -> Staged

4.1. Checking the status of your files
	git status
	git status -s
When git finds untracked files, it won't start including it in your commit snapshots until you explicitly tell it to do so.
4.2. Tracking New Files
	git add <file name>
example to add a folder "Python Practices": git add Python\ Practices/
And after this, use git status to check again. If you see "Your branch is up-to-date with 'origin/master'. Changes to be committed: ...", at this point, the files are staged, and waiting for to be committed.

4.3 Staging Modified Files
If you change a previously tracked file and run your git status command again, you will get something like "Changes not staged for commit: ...". To stage it, you run the git add command to stage files.

4.4 Ignoring Files
	.gitignore

4.5 Viewing your staged and unstaged changes
	git diff 
This shows you the exact lines added and removed --- the patch, as it were.
If you want to see what you've staged that will go into your next commit, you can use 
	git diff --staged
or
	git diff -cached

4.6 Committing your changes
Note that unstaged files won't go into this commit. They will just stay as modified on your disk.
	git commit
You can also do 
	git commit -a
So that you can skip staging, and all tracked files will automatically staged before commit.

4.7 Removing files
	git rm

4.8 Moving Files
	git mv <file_from> <file_to>

5. Viewing the Commit History
	git log
	git log -p -2
	git log --stat

6. Undoing Things
	git commit --amend

7. Working with Remotes
7.1 Showing your remotes
To see which remote servers you have configures, you can run 
	git remote
or 
	git remote -v
7.2 Adding remote repository
	git remote add <shortname> <url>

7.3 Fetching and Pulling from your remotes
To get data from your remote projects, you can run
	git fetch <remote>
or 
	git fetch origin
Note that, the git fetch command only downloads the data to your local repository --- it doesn't automatically merge it with any of your work or modify what you are currently working on.
You can use 
	git pull 
to automatically fetch and merge.

7.4 Pushing to your Remotes
	git push <remote> <branch>
or 
	git push origin master










